Marcello Deidda

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

CONTACTS

Phone: +447490216091

Email: info@marcellodeidda.com

Based in London

PERSONAL PROFILES

Portfolio

LinkedIn

<u>GitHub</u>

CodePen

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN: MongoDB, Express, React, Node

Python: Algorithms, Data Structs, OOP

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

JavaScript ES6

Databases: SQLite, PostgreSQL

CERTIFICATES

Front End Development Libraries

April 2023 – freeCodeCamp

Introduction to Computer Science

December 2022 – Harvard CS50

The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022

December 2022 - Udemy

Javascript Algorithms and Data Structs

December 2021 – freeCodeCamp

Responsive Web Design

November 2021 – freeCodeCamp

LANGUAGES

Italian – Native Speaker

English – Full proficiency

French – Full proficiency

Japanese – Limited Proficiency

Highly skilled Fullstack Developer specialising in the MERN stack with a recent completion of a Software Engineering Bootcamp funded by the DfE. Self-motivated and passionate about continuous learning, with a strong focus on personal development. Experienced teacher and excellent communicator.

PORTFOLIO

Full Stack - Node.js / Express / MongoDB:

BookApp // [Github] (IN PROGRESS)

Front End – HTML / CSS / Javascript / React.js:

- Prestissimo // [Github] (IN PROGRESS)
- Work Session Pacer // [Github]
- Rating Stars // [Github]
- Finance Calculators Web // [Github]

Software Development – Python / SQLite:

Ebookstore database // [Github]

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Bootcamp

University of Manchester & HyperionDev

November 2022 - February 2023

- Completed with 100% marks, ranking 2nd out of 300 students
- Developed proficiency in Python, OOP, HTML, CSS, SQLite

Fullstack Developer

Self-employed December 2020 – Current

- Focusing on portfolio front-end, back-end and full-stack projects.
- Continuously expanding skills through targeted courses.
- Currently developing BookApp, a reading-focused social media platform.
- Main technologies used: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, SQLite, Python.

Violinist and music teacher

Self-employed September 2015 – Current

- Performances in chamber music and orchestral settings
- Teaching violin, piano and music theory to students of 4 to 80yo
- Preparation for graded music exams with a 100% success rate

EDUCATION

Master's Degree, Advanced Instrument Studies

Guildhall School of Music & Drama, UK 2015 – 2016

Diploma di Violino (Bachelor degree equivalent)

Conservatorio di Musica di Cagliari, Italy 2011

Diploma di Liceo Scientifico (A-level equivalent)

Liceo scientifico statale "A. Pacinotti", Italy 2010

Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Literature, History, Philosophy, English, Latin, Arts